molochiy.ivan@gmail.com

IVAN MOLOCHIY

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Profile

I have more than 14 years of commertial experience in architectural design, development and maintaining microservices, web applications, REST API's and background services using (but not limited to) Golang and Java

Skills

Hard Skills

Golang
Java/Spring
Javascript
RDBMS NoSQL
Docker Kubernetes
Git Mercurial etc
Linux, OS X, Windows
Architectural design

Soft skills

High emotional intelligence Flexible Decision Making Responsible Social Self-learner Quick on the uptake

Project Direction

Proven ability to design, develop, fix and unit test a wide variety of projects in different domains

Experience

Kyivstar / Kyivstar Tech Senior Golang Developer

Kyivstar Open Telecom

Architectural design, feature planning and development, support and maintanance of developer portal and API gateway for telecom platform

Planning and prioritizing project tasks and features

Identification and mitigation of potential risks or roadblocks

Providing technical guidance and mentorship to engineers

Conducting code reviews and setting coding standards and best practices

Contractor

2019-2020

2020-now

Senior Golang Developer

Teaching strategies

Feature development and bugfix of teaching process management solution Developed and supported features for planning studies and learning process

Edvantis

2017 - 2018

Senior Golang Developer

Drilling info

Involved in Natural resources management app development

Fixed and improved authentication and client entitlement services after Red Hat SSO migration Developed features for managing client assets

Lohika

2013-2017

Java developer

Trane

Responsible for development of energy management system

Implemented metrics calculation related to utilities (electricity, gas, water etc.) like regional rollup, usage prediction, budget projection etc.

Implemented alerting system and meter data filtering and interpolation

Fixed countless issues in background services and web application

Tidemarl

Development and bug fixing of enterprise performance management software Implemented user task scheduling services. Fixed thread pooling issues

N-IX 2011-2013

Java Developer

OpenText

Designed and developed mobile client build management app from scratch Lead junior members of the team

Developed HTTP resolve server for applications requested by client and administration UI application for it Reverse-engineered and bug fixed legacy application for build management Implemented and optimized fallback HTTP server for proprietary binary protocol

GlobalLogic 2010-2011

Java Developer

WDS

Implemented various background services and web application for phone showcase and retail

WeComn

Implemented data providing backend and integrated with user interface built with proprietary software Implemented certificate management portal for mobile client rebranding application

Nice Systems

Developed the extension for video streaming server Fixed threading/socket/JNI video publishing issues

Optimized performance of live streaming video publishing, integrated with video encoding software service

Education

Ivan Franko National University of Lviv Master of Applied Mathematics and Informatics

Personal activities

Songwriting	Festivals	Camping
Sound engineering	Gym	Reading
Playing guitar/bass	Gaming	Electronic engineering

Links

Up-to-date CV: iamgoroot.github.io

GitHub: github.com/iamgoroot

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/ivan-molochiy